thecricfanclub.com 2012-12-30

# The CRIC Fan Club - Policy of The CRIC Fan Club

The CRIC Fan Club Policy

Modified: July 23, 2008 

The terms and conditions of the privacy and security of your data and information are important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. 

The CRIC Fan Club adheres to the Privacy Principles that are complied with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003. 

We care about the privacy of our website visitors; this policy sets out how we will treat your personal information. 

**(1) What information do we collect?**

We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data:

  1. Information about your computer and about your visits to and during use of our website (such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and number of page views); 
  2. Information that you provide to us for the purpose of registering with us; 
  3. Information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our website services, email notifications and/or newsletters; 
  4. Any other information that you choose to send to us.

**(2) Cookies**

We use cookies on www.thecricfanclub.com website. A cookie can be described as a text file containing a string of characters. The text file is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser. 

**We use cookies and the information obtained from the cookie to improve our websites usability and for marketing purposes.**

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but if you are uncomfortable regarding cookies use, you can disable cookies on your computer by changing the settings in preferences or options menu in your browser. (For example, in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookies by clicking Tools, Internet Options, Privacy, and selecting Block all cookies using the sliding selector.) 

**(3) Using your personal data**

Personal data submitted on our website will be used for the purposes specified in this privacy policy. 

We may use your personal information to: 

  1. administer the website;
  2. improve your browsing experience by personalizing the website; 
  3. enable your use of the services available on the website; 
  4. send you general (non-marketing) commercial communications; 
  5. send you email notifications which you have specifically requested; 
  6. send to you [our newsletter and other] marketing communications (relating to our business [or the businesses of carefully-selected third parties] which we think may be of interest to you by email or similar technology (when you have specifically agreed to this). You can inform us at any time if you no longer require marketing communications to be sent by emailing us at info@thecricfanclub.com; 
  7. provide third parties with statistical information about our users but this information will not be used to identify any individual user; 
  8. deal with enquiries and complaints made by or about you relating to the website. 

We will not without your express consent provide your personal information to any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing. 

**(4) Other disclosures**

In addition to the disclosures reasonably necessary for the purposes identified elsewhere in this privacy policy, we may disclose information about you: 

  1. to the extent that we are required to do so by law; 
  2. in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings; 
  3. in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk);

We use your return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. 

Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information and we do not share your information with third (outside) parties. 

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. 

**(5) International data transfers**

Information that we collect may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this privacy policy. 

If you are in the European Union, information which you provide may be transferred to countries (including India) which do not have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the European Union. You expressly agree to such transfers. 

**(6) Security of your personal data**

We will take technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse of your personal data, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information. These actions and managerial procedures secure the information we collect online. 

Hence the fact that data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet. 

You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. We will not ask you for your password. 

**(7) Policy amendments**

We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes. 

**(8) Third party websites**

The website contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third party websites. 

**(9) Updating information**

Please let us know if the personal information which we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated. 

**(10) Disclaimer of Liability.**

The CRIC Fan Club shall not be responsible for and disclaims all liability for any loss, liability, damage (whether direct, indirect or consequential), personal injury or expense of any nature whatsoever 

**(11) Contact**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, practices of our website or our treatment of your personal data, please email us to info@thecricfanclub.com.
